今天的阅读主题是调试。
The topic of today's reading is debugging.
或者更确切地说，如何避免完全调试，或者至少
Or rather how to avoid debugging entirely, or at least
当你不得不做的时候要保持轻松。
to keep it easy when you have to do it.
我们将讨论两个一般的方法
We're going to talk about two general ways
以避免痛苦的调试。
to avoid painful debugging.
首先，通过设计使错误变得不可能。
First, making bugs impossible by design.
我们将回顾一些我们已经掌握的技术
We'll review some techniques that we've already
静态检查，动态检查，
talked about, static checking, dynamic checking,
以及不变性。
and immutability.
第二，将bug定位到程序的一小部分
Second, localizing bugs to a small part of the program
这样就更容易找到虫子了。
so that finding the bug becomes easier.
我们会看到一些新的想法，主张，
We'll see some new ideas for this, assertions,
增量开发和范围最小化。
incremental development, and scope minimization.
好吧，我们开始吧。
OK, let's get started.